Walt Wells

Data Science Portfolio: www.www.mwells.github.io
646.515.7882 walt.p.wells@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE:

To obtain a position that would allow me to implement my data science skills and experience with open data to solve challenging problems and advance company goals.

EDUCATION:

CUNY

Master of Science in Data Science – Aug. 2018 Indiana University

Bachelor of Arts in Ethnomusicology and Folklore – Dec. 2001

EXPERIENCE

Center for Computational Science Research

Director of Operations / Data Science - Feb. 2015 - Present

- Managed stakeholders for data science 501c3 that operates the Open Commons Consortium, BloodPAC, and the Data Mining Group.
- Facilitate relationships with NASA and NOAA to openly redistribute satellite data.
- Release and community manager for PMML and PFA, standards in predictive analytic deployment.
- Community and development manager for petabyte scale science clouds.
- Organized Data Group, Data Experience, and Data Modeler working groups for national scale liquid biopsy data sharing project.
- BI analysis and data modeling for allocating available community resources.
- Governance for data contribution, data access, authentication and authorization for multiple major projects.

Operations Manager - April 2012 - Feb. 2015

PUBLICATIONS

- The Matsu Wheel: a reanalysis framework for Earth satellite imagery in data commons (Maria T. Patterson, Robert L. Grossman, Vuong Ly, Daniel J. Mandl, Walt Wells, et all) International Journal of Data Science and Analytics, 2017
- Collaborating to Compete: Blood Profiling Atlas in Cancer (BloodPAC) Consortium (Robert L. Grossman, Lauren Leiman, Walt Wells, et all), Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics, 2017
- The OCC NOAA Data Commons: First Year Experiences (Zach Flamig, Robert L. Grossman, Maria T. Patterson, Walt Wells), AMS Companion, 2017
- A Case for Data Commons: Towards Science as a Service (Robert L. Grossman, Allison Heath, Mark Murphy, Maria T. Patterson, Walt Wells), IEEE CISE, 2016
- The Matsu Wheel: A Cloud-based Framework for Efficient Analysis and Reanalysis
 of Earth Satellite Imagery (Robert L. Grossman, Maria T. Patterson, Matthew
 Handy, Vuong Ly, Ray Powell, Collin Bennett, Daniel J. Mandl, Walt Wells, James
 Pivarski), IEEE Big Data Service 2016
- The Design of a Community Science Cloud: The Open Science Data Cloud Perspective (Robert L Grossman, Matthew Greenway, Allison P Heath, Ray Powell, Walt Wells, Kevin White, Malcolm Atkinson, Joe J Mambretti, et all), High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage and Analysis (SCC), 2012 SC Companion

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

Experience with member driven data science non-profits focused on accelerating innovation and discovery through management of open data ecosystems and standards in predictive analytics. Fast learner, problem solver with diverse experiences in data science, open data, nonprofits and music. Works independently as well as in a team setting, adapts quickly based on project requirements

SKILLS

Code:

- R
- Python
- SQL
- Code Notebooks

Resources:

- AWS
- OpenStack / Ceph
- Hadoop / Spark

Data:

- Statistics / Probability
- Visualization
- Predictive Modeling
- RecSys, NLP
- Acquisition, Munging, and Management

Other:

- Open Data
- Data Governance
- Project Management
- Nonprofit Management

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Administrator - Cause Effective

Aug 2004 - Apr 2012

NYC nonprofit focused on resource development.

Independent Professional Musician

Jan. 2003 - Present

Musician / Composer / Film-Score / Co-Founder Jones Street Station, LLC.

